
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <channel>
   <title>reddit on a8b.io</title>
   <link>https://www.a8b.io/tags/reddit/</link>
   <description>Recent content in reddit on a8b.io</description>
   <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 15:10:56 -0700</lastBuildDate>
   
       <atom:link href="https://www.a8b.io/tags/reddit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
   
     <item>
       <title>How I got 10k post karma on reddit with (and without) fast.ai</title>
       <link>https://www.a8b.io/posts/10k-karma-reddit-bot/</link>
       <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 15:10:56 -0700</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.a8b.io/posts/10k-karma-reddit-bot/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.a8b.io/images/reddit/reddit_badge.png#mid&#34; alt=&#34;My reddit profile with 10,088 post karma&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Profile image made by AI Gahaku&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in late 2006 two of my best friends and I just starting college took ENG105 at Arizona State University. The most memorable thing from that class was the textbook called &amp;ldquo;Everything&amp;rsquo;s an Argument&amp;rdquo;, the title of which we used as justification to argue about mundane topics in jest. A year or so later one of these friends and I put together a spreadsheet of 20 or so high-level achievements called Everything&amp;rsquo;s a Contest. This includes items like &amp;ldquo;Watch the IMDB top 250 movies&amp;rdquo; (which has notably changed since then), &amp;ldquo;Photograph a live grizzly bear in the wild&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Have something named after you&amp;rdquo; (which couldn&amp;rsquo;t be done by anyone you know personally). On this list was also &amp;ldquo;Get 10,000 (post) karma on Reddit&amp;rdquo;. Despite our heated discussions about what should be on this list and the criteria for success none of us ever really did anything substantial to complete any of these goals. In early 2020 I decided I should finish more of what I start, and so I decided to tackle one of these long-standing contests. But I wanted to kill two birds with one stone. I was going to do it with AI, since I wanted to apply AI to more real-life problems. I&amp;rsquo;m a huge proponent of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fast.ai/&#34;&gt;fast.ai&lt;/a&gt; and I love the way you can tackle real problems quickly with its high-level abstractions. For someone trying to get into AI I would highly recommend using it as a framework and going through the associated materials. This is a post about how I used AI and other strategies to gain ~10,000 post karma on Reddit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;approach&#34;&gt;Approach&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content on Reddit, in general, falls into two categories: generative (original content) and aggregative (posting found content). Trying to automate generating content to post would be implementing something like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://imgflip.com/ai-meme&#34;&gt;imgflip AI meme generator&lt;/a&gt; and posting resulting content to r/memes. While the memes that are generated are an amusing juxtaposition of tropes, they generally aren&amp;rsquo;t as good as memes that are generated by human users skilled in the art of observational comedy. Try the meme generator out and you&amp;rsquo;ll see what I mean. At some point, I did try posting one of those just to see how well it did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.a8b.io/images/reddit/3migr03n6m251.jpg#mid&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;I went through about 100 auto generated memes before I got this. This post got ~35 points with the title &amp;#39;An AI generated this meme. Good to know it&amp;#39;s putting its sentience to good use.&amp;#39;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other approach would be finding content online and reposting it which I&amp;rsquo;m calling the aggregative approach. I chose this route because while generating high-quality content is more interesting it&amp;rsquo;s also far more challenging and involved. With the aggregative approach, rather than being disadvantaged in that you are trying to catch up to the &amp;ldquo;human quality&amp;rdquo; of content a computer is at the advantage since the primary differentiator between posters is the ability to search through large amounts of content and speed (who finds and posts something first). In particular, I ended up looking at new based subreddits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are little chances of things being a repost if you post fast enough&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are lots of quality candidates to post being generated frequently all over the internet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tend to have large member bases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of the content on the news subreddits comes from the same set of known sites that are easy to enumerate for watching and crawling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&#34;airtable-embed&#34; src=&#34;https://airtable.com/embed/shr9FUw82wAZBoQwn?backgroundColor=cyan&amp;viewControls=on&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; onmousewheel=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;533&#34; style=&#34;background: transparent; border: 1px solid #ccc;&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Domains for all the &gt; 1 score articles from /r/business in the last week (recorded on 2020/10/29) with their counts of occurence. This illustrates how a few sites supply the majority of the content for news based subreddits with over half the articles coming from the top 5 sites.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should note that I have to use my primary account for this (not using a novelty account was a requirement to accomplishing this task). At this point, I could go the spam route, and forego the need for AI at all by simply crawling certain news websites and spamming articles to relevant subreddits. In general spamming on reddit is looked down upon, thought I believe it&amp;rsquo;s up to the discretion of the subreddit moderators as far as I know. While in theory I might have gotten away with it or used some sort of generic rate-limiting and hope for the best, I wanted my bot to be more like a productive member of the community submitting thoughtful content, rather than a spam bot that would be the bane of its existence until forcibly removed since I needed it to run long-term on the same account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically for news subreddits I targeted /r/business and /r/worldnews, somewhat arbitrarily and somewhat because those areas seemed interesting to me. /r/business was relatively small (577k members) and low frequency for a news subreddit so it seemed approachable as a first target. The goal was to build a web crawler to watch popular business news sites (like the ones I listed in the table above) that would leverage an NLP-based article classifier to determine if the article was worthy of being posted (had a high chance of receiving upvotes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setup&#34;&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;finding-and-loading-posts&#34;&gt;Finding and loading posts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To train the NLP model that will classify articles I need the article text for the article submitted to Reddit and their corresponding Reddit scores. Unfortunately, the official Reddit API limits the amount of historic post data you can retrieve to 1000 items. Therefore I grabbed historic posts from &lt;a href=&#34;https://pushshift.io/&#34;&gt;pushshift.io&lt;/a&gt; using code I shamelessly adapted from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.osrsbox.com/blog/2019/03/18/watercooler-scraping-an-entire-subreddit-2007scape/&#34;&gt;WaterCooler: Scraping an Entire Subreddit (/r/2007scape)&lt;/a&gt;. The output file of the script has individual lines like the one below, containing a JSON object of a post per line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;CALIPHATEMEDIA&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;author_flair_css_class&amp;quot;: null, &amp;quot;author_flair_text&amp;quot;: null, &amp;quot;brand_safe&amp;quot;: true, &amp;quot;can_mod_post&amp;quot;: false, &amp;quot;contest_mode&amp;quot;: false, &amp;quot;created_utc&amp;quot;: 1514767344, &amp;quot;domain&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;caliphatemedia.info&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;full_link&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/business/comments/7nc5yf/south_korea_to_regulate_bitcoin_trading_further/&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;7nc5yf&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;is_crosspostable&amp;quot;: false, &amp;quot;is_reddit_media_domain&amp;quot;: false, &amp;quot;is_self&amp;quot;: false, &amp;quot;is_video&amp;quot;: false, &amp;quot;locked&amp;quot;: false, &amp;quot;num_comments&amp;quot;: 0, &amp;quot;num_crossposts&amp;quot;: 0, &amp;quot;over_18&amp;quot;: false, &amp;quot;parent_whitelist_status&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;all_ads&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;permalink&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;/r/business/comments/7nc5yf/south_korea_to_regulate_bitcoin_trading_further/&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;pinned&amp;quot;: false, &amp;quot;retrieved_on&amp;quot;: 1514841750, &amp;quot;score&amp;quot;: 1, &amp;quot;selftext&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;spoiler&amp;quot;: false, &amp;quot;stickied&amp;quot;: false, &amp;quot;subreddit&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;business&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;subreddit_id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;t5_2qgzg&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;subreddit_type&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;public&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;thumbnail&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;default&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;thumbnail_height&amp;quot;: 140, &amp;quot;thumbnail_width&amp;quot;: 140, &amp;quot;title&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;South korea to regulate bitcoin trading further with tougher measures&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;url&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;http://www.caliphatemedia.info/2017/12/south-korea-govt-to-introduce-tougher.html&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;whitelist_status&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;all_ads&amp;quot;}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;After generating a file with all the historic posts, I loaded the contents referenced by the &amp;ldquo;url&amp;rdquo; field of each JSON line into &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/slaveofcode/boilerpipe3&#34;&gt;boilerpipe3&lt;/a&gt; which can transform full HTML documents into simple text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.a8b.io/images/reddit/boilerpipe_example.png&#34; alt=&#34;An example of how boilerpipe3 works on the reuters article &amp;amp;ldquo;Amazon forecasts jump in holiday sales - and pandemic costs&amp;amp;rdquo;, removing (most of) the unecessary cruft.&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After loading the article text I did some processing to remove pages that didn&amp;rsquo;t load properly and to truncate articles to ~10k characters at most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;training-the-model&#34;&gt;Training the model&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I trained the NLP model for /r/business over a few days on approximately 271k articles from 2018-01-01 to mid-April 2020. I used an &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.fast.ai/text.models.awdlstm&#34;&gt;AWD_LSTM&lt;/a&gt; (e.g. language_model_learner(data_lm, AWD_LSTM, drop_mult=0.3) and text_classifier_learner(data, AWD_LSTM, drop_mult=0.5)) for the model with classification labels based on the score for neutral (0-10 points), okay (10-100), good (100-500), and great (500+). Note that the classes are kind of arbitrary and I&amp;rsquo;ve changed them around for different iterations and subreddits. The only thing I ended up paying attention to at runtime was the non-neutral class score, so this could have been a binary classifier or even better a classifier that looks at an individual article as a candidate for multiple subreddits rather than training an individual model per subreddit. For world news I had over double the number of articles, that I trained in 300k chunks due to memory limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-personal-business-news-aggregator&#34;&gt;My personal business news aggregator&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose a few sites (Business Insider, Reuters, Bloomberg, CNN, CNBC, BBC, etc.) based on some of the frequent sites I noticed for /r/business, and plopped them into a script and built a crawler using requests and BeautifulSoup. Every minute or so I&amp;rsquo;d crawl the site root for new links and process the linked page with boilerpipe and pass it through the NLP model for scoring. New pages with a non-neutral score of greater than 0.25 (an arbitrary threshold I picked for this particular model) would be flagged and emailed to me using AWS SNS. Initially, I relied on filtering these incoming suggestions and submitting the articles myself using the Reddit app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.a8b.io/images/reddit/example_email.png&#34; alt=&#34;An example email I received from my site poller that I called &amp;amp;ldquo;Reddit Postmaster&amp;amp;rdquo;.&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;automation&#34;&gt;Automation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, my site poller is acting as a personal news aggregator that I use to generate suggestions for things to post. To remove me from this loop there are a few &amp;ldquo;last mile&amp;rdquo; problems to solve. Coding up submitting via the Reddit API is easy enough, but I also need to automate gathering an appropriate title for the Reddit post and a final quality-check for the posts getting submitted. The page title is usually not good as a post title (for example containing redundancies like the site name) directly and needs to be reformatted or the title should instead be extracted from the content for example by picking the most appropriate h1 tag on the page. Rather than refining the model to be better at classifying articles and improve the accuracy of the scoring mechanism, and then coding a new component for extracting the title, I decided to try to encapsulate these tasks into a mechanical turk task and have humans as the final gate-keeper and title generator. I can take the results from these mechanical turk tasks and submit the articles to Reddit via the Reddit API utilizing those results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mechanical-turk&#34;&gt;Mechanical Turk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mechanical turk is a super neat resource for leveraging humans to complete small tasks for your application. It&#39;s great for augmenting AI applications and collecting data via labeling tasks for them. But using it effectively isn&#39;t without difficulties. The important thing to know about mechanical turk is that many workers on the platform are (sensibly) optimizing for task completion quantity. When using a custom qualifier for tasks, ensure the qualification you&#39;re looking for is not apparent from the question. Similarily a bad HIT (human intelligence task) would be one where you ask the user to read an article and check some box if they think it belongs in some category. For example, I did this with /r/worldnews candidates to ensure that among other things didn&#39;t pertain to US news, however the first fully automated submission I made to /r/worldnews was &#34;Johnson &amp; Johnson to stop selling baby powder in the United States&#34; which was removed after receiving 42 upvotes since US internal news is banned on /r/worldnews. Make sure the work you assign at least appears as though you will look at the individual results (e.g. use text input boxes at least once). Be careful and clear about what you&#39;re asking and reduce the opportunities for human error. Asking for the user to supply an article title, while well-intentioned results in some users writing poor article titles rather than copying the article title if they can&#39;t think of a good one. A better task would be to ask the user to identify and copy the article title as it appears in the article since that has more reliable quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.a8b.io/images/reddit/post_notification.png&#34; alt=&#34;A new email letting me know when a post was submitted on my behalf.&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&#34;airtable-embed&#34; src=&#34;https://airtable.com/embed/shroixznK6muAsosc?backgroundColor=yellow&amp;viewControls=on&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; onmousewheel=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;533&#34; style=&#34;background: transparent; border: 1px solid #ccc;&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;All items detected and/or posted by &#34;Reddit Postmaster&#34;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may notice that we only post a few things per day at most. In fact, our bot is probably under posting. One strategy we could adopt here would be to lower the threshold as time goes on to incentivize posting more content as each post comes with a relatively limited downside (a few downvotes then into obscurity) and a very high upside potential. While we want to avoid being spammy, our behavior is probably a little too conservative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alignment&#34;&gt;Alignment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The alignment problem (in AI) is when your system performs the way you told it to, for example optimizing upvotes, but it does so in a way that goes against what you actually want. For example regarding the post I referenced earlier related to US news that was posted to /r/worldnews and then removed by a moderator. While the post did get some upvotes (~42) it violated my expectation and preference that the bot would follow the rules. The problem lies in the lack of negative examples of what the bot shouldn&amp;rsquo;t do. Because /r/worldnews isn&amp;rsquo;t full of US news articles that are downvoted and removed for violating the rules, my bot has a lack of examples of what it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t do. We could teach it the rules in the future augmenting the dataset with things that violate the rules with very negative scores. The problem of AI alignment is deeper though, as while I did identify one thing I didn&amp;rsquo;t want the bot to do, there are many unstated things I also don&amp;rsquo;t want the bot to do that it might do to try to optimize upvotes (for example posting photoshopped pictures, offensive content, making jokes about my mother, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-means&#34;&gt;Other means&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In total over 1.5 months of running the system on two subreddits, I was able to garner around 3.7k Reddit karma. Unfortunately, I never got a big hit on /r/worldnews. I got close on some occasions, such as the article about the grandma being forced to remove photos due to GDPR. However, another article covering the same thing (which later had 20k+ points) was already posted and my post was marked as being covered by another article. For the highly competetive /r/worldnews my mechanical turk tasks were taking just a little too long. This could have likely been remedied by increasing the monetary reward associated with each task. I say &amp;ldquo;around&amp;rdquo; 3.7k because the karma count for each post, in a quantum fashion, actually fluctuates slightly when you attempt to observe it. This is actually to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/OutOfTheLoop/comments/21id6d/why_do_number_of_downvotes_on_my_posts_fluctuate/&#34;&gt;thwart spam bots&lt;/a&gt;. So where did the other 6.3k come from? I got tired of waiting and went for some low hanging fruit I could tackle manually. /r/askreddit was an obvious one, coming up with an engaging question can easily get you 20k+ karma. /r/memes was an entertaining one, but difficult to breakthrough. What ended up being the winner was /r/todayilearned. I dug through &amp;ldquo;interesting facts&amp;rdquo; lists on the internet and simply found things that weren&amp;rsquo;t posted and repackaged the facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.a8b.io/images/reddit/the_winning_post.png&#34; alt=&#34;Slightly anti-climactic for ~14 years in the making.&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly enough, even with such a large number of upvotes on a single post, all the upvotes did not count linearly towards my post karma count and I was still short some, which I was able to grind away on random subreddits (read: terrible memes and dog pictures).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, a bit of manual effort beat out my months of computing time. There is no doubt that I would have automatically crossed the 10k mark and could have easily gone to any arbitrary amount given enough time running my post bot. But still I suppose this reinforces the idea you probably shouldn&amp;rsquo;t go around looking for problems to apply a specific tool to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Principles</title>
       <link>https://www.a8b.io/posts/principles/</link>
       <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 15:02:52 -0700</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.a8b.io/posts/principles/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Before writing anything on this blog I wanted to share some principles that I have been (more or less) using in life and that may subsequently be referred to within this blog. While these may seem obvious upon reading, it&amp;rsquo;s the careful application of these that I consider important and not simply the knowledge of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;whatever-you-do-do-it-in-depth&#34;&gt;Whatever you do, do it in depth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever you do, you should do it in depth. This also implies you must pick what you do carefully. You may not be well suited (due to your natural interests or current capabilities) to do everything. Once you pick something you should do your best to learn, explore, immerse yourself, and make an outsized impact in that area. This tends to be a natural desire if you pick something that you fundamentally care about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reason for thinking this at the organizational level is that many economies of scale are &amp;ldquo;winners take all&amp;rdquo;. If you truly believe in what you&amp;rsquo;re doing you usually desire to scale what you&amp;rsquo;re doing up to the largest possible impact. But in a winner take all economy the best X will likely have some 80% of the market share and the remaining 20% will be split across its competitors. Most businesses that scale well are providing platforms that connect services, businesses, or people to one another (rather than offering the services or content itself), rather than provide services directly. Think Uber as a platform that connects drivers to passengers compared to a localized taxi company. Network effects usually compound the advantages that any one platform has over another (in Uber&amp;rsquo;s case say due to the number of drivers and riders) and therefore it pays exponentially to be the best. When dealing with things that can scale very large like this, focusing on the one thing that you can be the best at will yield better results than focusing on many things, even if you are competent at those many things. Even when dealing with things which don&amp;rsquo;t scale, it pays to be top of mind to a consumer in some category, rather than 2nd in many.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the individual level, once you start working on a particular project you gather a lot of context. As you leave that project you lose the context. Context switching can be very costly and is one reason why you want to focus on one thing at a time in depth. Once you have that context and the time set aside to work on that thing, the marginal cost of improving the process you&amp;rsquo;re going through is smaller compared to if you set that improvement aside to come back to later. And the benefits of such process improvements are usually much larger than just the scope of your current project or work. When you dig deep into a project you notice more of those potential improvements and gain an understanding of the domain you are operating in that is itself a compounding investment for the future. In addition, going in-depth on a project can foster a sense of ownership and craftsmanship, especially if you care deeply about what you&amp;rsquo;re doing. That craftsmanship can be a source of enjoyment and motivation in and of itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a learning perspective going in-depth means doing your best to understand the fundamental concepts of what you&amp;rsquo;re learning so that your time is a compounding investment. Gaining an intuition is usually a more important outcome than memorizing some surface-level facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All time is not equal. In many things, a linear increase in quality time you spend on a particular thing can have an exponential benefit as you make improvements that span to other people, teams, organizations, or yourself in the future. Choosing the projects where your time can be leveraged to produce outsized gains, and then pushing a lot of time into those projects is an effective strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pitfalls&#34;&gt;Pitfalls&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the personal level, the idea of going in-depth on one particular thing can also be interpreted as hyperfocus. That can lead to tunnel vision and your inability to synthesize information across projects and areas which is critical for creativity. Hyper specialization can lead to the Einstellung effect, colloquially if you have a hammer, everything is a nail. It is important to recognize that to solve a problem you must sometimes focus away from it, and look to different, wide-ranging areas for inspiration. Focusing on solving the problem is not the same as focusing on the problem. Furthermore going in-depth to solve a problem may mean going through a wide and broad range of things for inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the idea of going in-depth on a project could be superficially interpreted as spending more time on something is automatically better. However, the activities you do during that time are important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, the effective use of your time is up to you. Principles are guidelines and are meant to be followed to the spirit, and not to letter if you understand why you&amp;rsquo;re doing what you&amp;rsquo;re doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;parallel-ideas&#34;&gt;Parallel Ideas&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do less, then obsess&amp;rdquo; from Great at Work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great by Choice talks about Amundsen and Scott&amp;rsquo;s race to the south pole, and how Amundsen focused on a solid plan and mastering a single means of transport (dog sledding) whereas Scott diversified and did not go as in-depth into various facets of the planning, relying on systemic redundancies that ultimately failed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do something that you can be the best in the world at, part of &amp;ldquo;the hedgehog concept&amp;rdquo; from Good to Great&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The idea of building a &amp;ldquo;Monopoly&amp;rdquo; from Zero to One&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edison (biography by Edmund Morris) exhibited the idea of going in-depth, trying thousands of variants of lightbulb filaments, thousands of plants as sources of rubber, and so on to solve various problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steve Jobs (biography by Walter Isaacson) was someone who went in-depth on almost everything he did. Refer to Creative Selection by Ken Kocienda to see stories of how he dove into every detail of the iPhone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The idea of niche specialization from The Passion Economy by Adam Davidson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less is More from the book Range&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stick-to-things&#34;&gt;Stick to things&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stick to things. This means that you should be careful about what you pick to work on. This is especially pertinent when also following the first principle, whatever you do, do it in depth. Value is only realized when you finish whatever you&amp;rsquo;re working on. Most projects don&amp;rsquo;t deliver incremental value (e.g. a half published book is not valuable to anyone but yourself). Therefore either work on incremental value projects or stick to the projects you work on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tend to suffer from analysis paralysis, or a form of it, where I frequently switch projects and priorities only to find myself looking back and realizing I have not finished many of them. In general, you learn more from a project you finished (and that sucks) than from one you didn&amp;rsquo;t. It&amp;rsquo;s also generally better to do something that is only partly useful than nothing at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pitfalls-1&#34;&gt;Pitfalls&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By contrast, knowing when to give up is a difficult thing. Not everything should be pursued indefinitely or under all conditions. It may make a lot of sense for a startup to pivot at any given moment, though doing so with care and forethought. As for most things, what counts is the intention and reason. Giving up to work on another thing due to a minute change in priorities, being more excited about another thing in the short term, self-doubting, being unsure about the outcome, or even just being more excited about the idea of things than doing them are all invalid reasons to give up on something. Having a rational reason to give up may be valid, but beware the distinction between rational reasons and a rationalization. Also, keep in mind that what you&amp;rsquo;re working on should be worth the time spent. If it&amp;rsquo;s not worth 10 years then it is likely not worth 10 minutes of your time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing to be aware of is the distinction between sticking to something and falling into a habit. Just because you&amp;rsquo;ve always done something a certain way doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that you need to continue doing that to stick to it, that&amp;rsquo;s not the kind of tenacity I&amp;rsquo;m talking about. It&amp;rsquo;s very difficult to evaluate your life objectively, and people tend to evaluate potential outcomes relative to their current positions and tend to value losing certain things more than gaining others. For example, quitting a well-paid job to pursue an independent business idea with no guarantee of funding or success can be very difficult since the idea of losing the job is overvalued due to loss aversion and the idea of doing something new and risky could be undervalued due to the probabilistic nature of the outcome and the comfort of not changing. Reframing your decisions in more absolute terms can be a way to deal with loss aversion and stagnation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;parallel-ideas-1&#34;&gt;Parallel Ideas&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grit (from the book Grit by Angela Duckworth)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edison (see biography by Edmund Morris) was a great example of someone willing to spend decades on a specific area of problems. He is also attributed to saying success is 1% inspiration and 99% perspiration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;John Keats finished the 4000 line poem Endymion, even though he hated it around ¾ of the way through, as it was a test he had set to himself of his abilities and creativity. He did this poem as an exercise in tenacity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paul Graham and others who talk about startups frequently highlight the necessity of persistence in face of the numerous challenges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The book range talks about the potential pitfall of having too much grit, and that similarly &amp;ldquo;The important trick…is staying attuned to whether switching is simply a failure of perseverance or astute recognition that better matches are available.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beware of false fails from Loonshots by Safi Bakhal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;produce-more-and-consume-less&#34;&gt;Produce more and consume less&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produce more and consume less is a reminder that consumption for consumption&amp;rsquo;s sake does not produce anything meaningful. It can feel very productive to go read ten books, but on the other hand, you can also learn a lot of things that stick while creating value. A project in the hand is worth at least a dozen in the bush. Choose something worthy, stick to it, and learn from doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pitfalls-2&#34;&gt;Pitfalls&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean don&amp;rsquo;t rely on the wisdom of others. Just that there is an extent to the utility of learning from others without implementing those things in practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;parallel-ideas-2&#34;&gt;Parallel Ideas&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The book Mastery focuses on the apprenticeship and the necessity to practice your skills in a real environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bill Gates, Steve Jobs and others who did not pursue a traditional education (though were very astute learners) by dropping out of college are examples of people who learned through doing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great at Work highlights the importance of not just learning but looping over your behaviors and iterating in the real world on the things you want to improve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-should-be-concrete&#34;&gt;Goals should be concrete&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract goals can be useful for defining your desired intentions but when it comes to putting them down on paper and measuring yourself against them they can prove difficult. The primary problem with abstract goals is that you get caught in the inability to define a consistent course of action over time and a way to measure them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Become a good cook&amp;rdquo; is a bad goal because you are unable to determine what to do to achieve it and how to measure what a &amp;ldquo;good cook&amp;rdquo; is. &amp;ldquo;Work through and master La technique by Jacques Pepin&amp;rdquo; would be a better goal. There is a clearly defined course of action and a way to measure yourself against that goal (how many of the techniques I&amp;rsquo;ve worked through). My intention can still be to become a good cook, but what I should hold myself to when I&amp;rsquo;m living my day to day life should be the course I set up. KPI setting and measuring can be another way to measure yourself against complex goals. TODO lists are a great mechanism for short term actionable goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pitfalls-3&#34;&gt;Pitfalls&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everything should be a goal. And goals do not preclude the necessity for a higher purpose of mission that ties your activities together. In general, having goals may actually make you less satisfied with your life, therefore not everything should be a goal. Try to have some things that you do just because you want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beware of Goodhart&amp;rsquo;s law, which is that once a measure becomes a target it ceases to be a good measure. To phrase it in another way the gap between what you intend to measure, and what you actually measure will be realized, so choose carefully what you&amp;rsquo;re measuring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;parallel-ideas-3&#34;&gt;Parallel Ideas&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measure what matters by John Doerr&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting Things Done by David Allen talks about the importance of making your next steps actionable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;understand-and-respect-motivations&#34;&gt;Understand and respect motivations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Context can be everything. You can start a company because, as Max Levechin says you realize you can&amp;rsquo;t work for anyone else. You can do it because you want to do something important and what you&amp;rsquo;re doing now doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel important like Tony Hsieh. You can do it because you want to have an outsized (hopefully positive) impact on the world like Steve Jobs, maybe even in a specific (and personal) way. A person may resonate with any of those narratives and more. It is important to recognize what resonates with you and what drives you to do things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For myself, the idea of &amp;ldquo;doing something successful for the sake of success&amp;rdquo; is simply the hedonic treadmill. I respond to internal motivators more than external success factors. I&amp;rsquo;d likely never start a social media company or advertising company. For one thing, because I don&amp;rsquo;t particularly care about those things, and I may see them as having a large but potentially negative impact on the world. Recognizing what things I do think are important and the things I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about and respecting those things are important. Don&amp;rsquo;t ignore your sense of what you like to do and what you think is meaningful. You will have more success doing something you care about that is hard, than doing something you don&amp;rsquo;t that is easy. In addition when dealing with an organization having a higher purpose can bring a team together and define a culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never assume that another person has the same motivations as you. Each person operates differently and it can be easy to be rubbed the wrong way when you try to view their actions through your motivations. As long as they&amp;rsquo;re doing good work try to understand what motivates them and leverage that rather than conflict with it. How you frame things can be very important to people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pitfalls-4&#34;&gt;Pitfalls&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s usually helpful to communicate your motivations to other people so that they know what you&amp;rsquo;re going to be motivated to work on and what you won&amp;rsquo;t. Be careful not to look down on others who don&amp;rsquo;t have the same motivations as you, especially if those motivations are more basic (such as in pursuit of titles, money, etc.). Prefer to work with people who are motivated by non-personal agendas though, as they&amp;rsquo;ll be more likely to help you if your goals align with what they want (regardless of credit or optics).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;parallel-ideas-4&#34;&gt;Parallel Ideas&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All of the &amp;ldquo;Why&amp;rdquo; books from Simon Sinek&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Passion and Purpose principle from Great at Work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Warren Buffett famously quoted that he tap dances to work. He claims to love what he does and would likely not be as successful in doing something else&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Inside-Out&amp;rdquo; chapter from the 7 habits of highly effective people highlights the effect of different motivations on outcomes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Culture Code highlights the importance of establishing a higher purpose as a means to create an effective organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the book Range the context principle is the idea that the behaviors people exhibit are highly dependent on the context in which they operate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prefer-probabilistic-over-deterministic-thinking&#34;&gt;Prefer probabilistic over deterministic thinking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prefer probabilistic over deterministic thinking. I think deterministic thinking is the default human behavior and that thinking in probabilities is quite difficult since anecdotally to each person something either happens or it doesn&amp;rsquo;t. As an example, I casually mentioned to my friend that the success of most business ventures is fairly low (maybe &amp;lt; 10%) and that I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t assume that I am impervious to those statistics and therefore should assume that my business venture has a low chance of success. This made her question why I would pursue my business at all if it was doomed to failure. As someone directing the business, my goal should be to do everything I can to prevent that failure (be productively paranoid), because I know that there is a large probability I could fail. To ignore the statistics would be bravado, and to succumb to them would be boring. To assume that I am practically guaranteed failure or success is a false dichotomy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great way in my mind to develop probabilistic thinking is to at least tread the waters of professional poker or gambling. Professional poker or gambling is not about luck but about expected values, and gaining an edge over the others at the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probabilistic thinking embraces individual failures. You do your best to play every hand as well as you can to gain an advantage over time, but when you do fail an individual hand you aren&amp;rsquo;t devastated because you know there will be failures. Life is not a pure game of deterministic skill, but one with variance and sometimes you can fail even when you play everything correctly. It&amp;rsquo;s important to accept the blame for your failures and correctly analyze why you failed. Blaming bad luck when you fail at something isn&amp;rsquo;t a good solution for winning more in the long run. Sometimes you fail when you don&amp;rsquo;t play things correctly and from that, it&amp;rsquo;s important to learn. You could also think about probabilistic thinking as being process-oriented rather than individual outcome-oriented. A growth mindset (believing that you can change your abilities over time) is something that also comes when you focus on the process as opposed to individual outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pitfalls-5&#34;&gt;Pitfalls&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking probabilistically you may find yourself relying on luck and going after a large number of opportunities. That can be an effective strategy especially for creative endeavors but you&amp;rsquo;ll need to recognize that luck favors the prepared. Once you find something in your search you still need to dig in and do it to the best of your abilities. You are never entitled to success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;parallel-ideas-5&#34;&gt;Parallel Ideas&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Growth Mindset from Mindset by Carol Dweck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thinking in Bets by Annie Duke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The game of poker (the biggest bluff by Maria Konnikova is a fun and adventurous introduction to the game for a non-player)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Warren Buffet (a proponent of value investing), one of the most successful investors in the world, tends to ignore market fluctuations and values long term results. One of the most important qualities in an investor is the emotional fortitude to weather market fluctuations while keeping in mind the true underlying value of the assets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fermi problems and thinking as mentioned in the book Range&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Return on Luck and being productively paranoid from Great by Choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confront the brutal facts from Good to Great&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Embrace reality and deal with it from Principles by Ray Dalio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
 </channel>
</rss>
